Clayton W. Seitz, Ph.D.

cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have a background in computer vision, machine learning, and mathematics. Recently, I have researched novel image generation methods based on deep learning. I also specialize in image/video processing, object detection, segmentation, and object tracking. These methods were applied in biological research.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosopy, Physics

2024

Purdue University

Master of Science, Physics

2021

University of Chicago

Bachelor of Science, Physics, Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University
Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Informatics (Math Focus), Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Researcher

2021-2024

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Designed diffusion models/score-based generative models and general computer vision techniques (object detection, segmentation, etc.) in PyTorch for modeling image datasets in super-resolution fluorescence microscopy
- Applied deep neural networks for three dimensional reconstruction of objects in microscopy images
- Applied general probabilistic models for high-dimensional imaging datasets and associated Bayesian methods for statistical inference tasks
- Developed novel hardware systems for super-resolution imaging of human cells

Graduate Researcher

2020-2021

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

- Investigated fundamental learning mechanisms in recurrent neural networks (RNNs) using dynamical models, mean-field theory, and time-series analysis.
- Designed and ran Monte Carlo simulations of spiking neural networks

Research Assistant

2018-2020

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Developed a scientific package in Python for high-throughput object detection and tracking
- Managed the package lifecycle and user training throughout the laboratory

AWARDS

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL 2020

Travel Award and Lightning Talk Invitation Physical Sciences in Oncology - Minneapolis, MN 2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship

2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Clayton Seitz[†], Donghong Fu[†], Mengyuan Liu, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. BRD4 phosphorylation regulates the structure of chromatin nanodomains. Physical Review Letters (In Review). https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.03.611057. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Uncertainty-aware localization microscopy by variational diffusion. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Quantum enhanced localization microscopy with a single photon avalanche diode array. In Review. 2024

> Maelle Locatelli[†], Josh Lawrimore[†], Hua Lin[†], Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS 12 July 2022; 119 (29): 1-11

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International 15 January 2022; 46 (5): 683-700

> Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 25 October 2021; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. Cytokine-induced transcriptional memory is evident in the kinetics of transcriptional bursts. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2022

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Programming Languages & Software: Linux, Bash, Python, R, PyTorch, C/C++, SQL, LaTeX, Git, Docker, SLURM, AWS